What comes into your mind when you think of British food?
一想到英国菜，你脑海里会浮现出什么？
Probably fish and chips, or a Sunday dinner of meat and two vegetables.
大概是炸鱼薯条，或者周日一份肉配两样蔬菜的正餐吧。
But is British food really so uninteresting?
但英国菜真的这么乏味吗？
Even though Britain has a reputation for less-than-impressive cuisine, it is producing more top-class chefs who appear frequently on our television screens and whose recipe books frequently top the bestseller lists.
尽管英国菜肴的名声向来不怎么样，但英国正涌现出越来越多的顶级厨师，他们频频出现在我们的电视屏幕上，写的菜谱书也常常高居畅销书榜首。
It’s thanks to these TV chefs rather than any advertising campaign that Britons are turning away from meat-and-two-veg and ready-made meals and becoming more adventurous in their cooking habits.
英国人正逐渐告别“一肉两菜”和现成餐食，在烹饪习惯上也变得更敢于尝试，这要归功于这些电视厨师，而不是什么广告宣传。
It has recently been reported that the number of those sticking to a traditional diet is slowly declining and around half of Britain’s consumers would like to change or improve their cooking in some way.
据最近报道，坚持传统饮食的人数正在缓慢下降，约一半的英国消费者想在某些方面改变或改进自己的烹饪方式。
There has been a rise in the number of students applying for food courses at UK universities and colleges.
申请英国各大学和学院食品类课程的学生人数有所增加。
It seems that TV programmes have helped change what people think about cooking.
看来，电视节目促使人们改变了对烹饪的看法。
According to a new study from market analysts, 1 in 5 Britons say that watching cookery programmes on TV has encouraged them to try different food.
据市场分析人士的一项新研究，五分之一的英国人表示，看电视上的烹饪节目促使他们尝试了不同的食物。
Almost one third say they now use a wider variety of ingredients than they used to, and just under 1 in 4 say they now buy better quality ingredients than before.
近三分之一的人说，他们现在使用的配料种类比过去更多；略低于四分之一的人说，他们现在买的配料质量比以前更好。
One in four adults say that TV chefs have made them much more confident about expanding their cookery knowledge and skills, and young people are also getting more interested in cooking.
四分之一的成年人说，电视厨师让他们在拓展烹饪知识和技能方面自信了许多；年轻人也对烹饪越来越感兴趣。
The UK’s obsession with food is reflected in television scheduling.
英国人对美食的痴迷在电视节目编排中可见一斑。
Cookery shows and documentaries about food are broadcast more often than before.
烹饪节目和美食纪录片播出得比以前更频繁了。
With an increasing number of male chefs on TV, it’s no longer “uncool” for boys to like cooking.
随着电视上的男厨师越来越多，男孩喜欢做饭不再是“不酷”的事了。